

Abu Saleh Muhammad Shaon

Full Stack PHP Developer | B.Sc. in CSE | PHP Zend Certified

Contact Information

- +880 1919453895
- <u>srabon.php@gmail.com</u>
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/as mshaon/

Career Objective

To be an outstanding Full Stack PHP Developer in any renowned organization and grow rapidly with increasing responsibilities.

Competencies

- PHP/Javascript/Node JS
- Laravel/Symfony/Yii/Cakphp
- Express/React/Vue/Angular
- AWS/Lambda/S3/SQS
- Rest API development
- Webpack/Babel/Gulp
- Database/MySQL/Oracle
- Any API Integration

Career Summary

13 year experienced full stack PHP developer, worked with the organizations of several nations, with having track record of accomplishing various heavy site development project, especially travel booking site, SASS application & ecommerce web application development projects.

Work Experience

Freelancer

(Aug 2021 – Continue)

Upwork

Accomplished Project:

Developed a POS software for Admin and Members panels

Sr. PHP Developer

(Jun 2020 – Jul 2021)

Worktable Pte Ltd, Singapore

Key Contributions:

- Built Rest API Engine of Digital Wallet
- Worked for developing e-commerce shopping platform
- Developed Admin portals, reports, security fixes, etc.

Sr. PHP Developer

(Mar 2015 – Apr 2020)

VroomVroom Pty Ltd, Australia

- Developed rental car booking platform engine (used The Rest API from the web and mobile)
- Kept lots of feature related to booking, such as:
 - airport retargeting,
 - loyalty program,
 - free update, etc.
- Offered almost 20 Suppliers around the world

Software Developer

(Sep 2014 – Oct 2015)

Moteel.com, Saudi Arabia

• Built Hotel Management Application using Ruby on Rails, Coffee Scripts, Node JS, etc.

Abu Saleh Muhammad Shaon

Full Stack PHP Developer | B.Sc. in CSE | PHP Zend Certified

<u>Development Tools</u> <u>Expertise</u>

- Linux/Docker/Nginx/PHPfpm
- Agile/Scrum/Jira/Slack
- GitHub/GitLab/bitbucket
- PHPStorm/Xdebug/UnitTest
- UML/ERD/FLOW diagram

Soft Skills

- Time Management
- Communication Skill
- Decision Making
- Team Building
- Attention to Detail
- Proactive
- Quick Support & Bug Fixing

<u>Language</u>

English: Fluent

• Bengali: Native or Bilingual

Sr. PHP Developer

Okdoit, Saudi Arabia

(Jan 2012 - Aug 2014)

Built Developed a task management application with email syntax using Laravel, Angular JS, Bootstrap, etc.

Web Developer

(Apr 2010 - Dec 2011)

Informatix Technologies, Bangladesh

- Developed a job site and many other projects
- Worked with Zend Framework and Codeignitor

Web Developer

(Mar 2009 – Mar 2010)

Bengals Solutions Ltd, Bangladesh

 Built small and medium applications with the Zend Framework, PHP, and MySQL

Educational Qualification

B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering

International Islamic University, Chittagong

Certification

- PHP Certified Engineer
 (https://www.zend-zce.com/en/yellow-pages/ZEND010646)
- UVA ACM Stats
 (https://www.dropbox.com/s/lsa6csmioshovyv/ACM_Profile_Abu_Saleh_Muhammad_Shaon.png?dl=o)